<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>languages on The B0ardside</title>
    <link>http://theb0ardside.com/tags/languages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in languages on The B0ardside</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://theb0ardside.com/tags/languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Lisp Like It&#39;s 1959</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/letslisp1959/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/letslisp1959/</guid>
      <description>Nicely delivered talk by Kristoffer Gronlund about the origins of the LISP language..
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizard Book</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/wizard-book-lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/wizard-book-lectures/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never made it very far through my copy of Abelson, Sussman and Sussman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Structure and Interpretation Of Computer Programs&amp;rsquo;, so I was super excited to find this whole series of lectures online with Harold and Gerald Jay presenting the text as a course. The lectures help a lot, making it a whole lot easier than just wading through the text yourself. I went deep over the weekend, watching the first four of them - My Lisp foo is getting strong!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Phillips - Scala Heresies</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/paulphillips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/paulphillips/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t see this actual talk, but pretty much the same one delivered the following evening - it gave me nightmares!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Presentation</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/gopresentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/gopresentation/</guid>
      <description>More and more I&amp;rsquo;ve been dabbling with Go, which, mainly due to Hacker News, i&amp;rsquo;ve been reading so many good things about. The syntax is super easy to pick up, but the killer feature seems to be the concurrency primitives - the Go Functions and message passing Channels seem like a super tight, rock solid implementation of Hoare&amp;rsquo;s Communicating Sequential Processes. The following video is a really succinct walk through of building a concurent multi-protocol chat application ala Chat Roulette.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
