<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cybernetics on The B0ardside</title>
    <link>http://theb0ardside.com/tags/cybernetics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cybernetics on The B0ardside</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://theb0ardside.com/tags/cybernetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leap Motion</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/leapmotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/leapmotion/</guid>
      <description>ooh, nice. Just saw this company mentioned in the comments of an HN thread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>some fav Velocity talks</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/somefavvelocitytalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/somefavvelocitytalks/</guid>
      <description>Velocity was on last week, and I was following along enviously on twitter - I&#39;m making a promise to myself that I&#39;ll be along in person next year!
Quite a few of the talks now appearing online - here&#39;s a couple I&#39;ve watched so far..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ono-Sendai SLB-10 ORB system</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/theonosendaislb10orbsystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/theonosendaislb10orbsystem/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#8220;The SLB-10 is the latest generation of ORB manufactured by Ono-Sendai, utilizing state of the art EM pulse powered flotation; archive-quality audio and visual recording capabilities; fully CMYK coloured, tactile holographic capability; and guaranteed always-on connection to your personal encrypted data storage facility.
ORBs have become so integral to our life and yet they are barely a 7 year old technology. It is worth reflecting on the brief history of these astounding devices, upon which we now rely so heavily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Von Neumann and the Institute For Advanced Study</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/vonneumannandtheinstituteforadvancedstudy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/vonneumannandtheinstituteforadvancedstudy/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve started reading George Dyson&#39;s &amp;#8220;Turing&#39;s Cathedral&amp;#8221;, and really enjoying it - I love reading the historical context of technological progress, feels like a lot of sociological reading, filling in another of the endless jigsaw pieces of a larger all-encompassing narrative.
Here&#39;s George Dyson doing a lecture on the material in the book :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>going google eyed</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/goinggoogleeyed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/goinggoogleeyed/</guid>
      <description>Ah, see, my comic is all true! :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the biology of code</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/thebiologyofcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/thebiologyofcode/</guid>
      <description>Fabulous piece and video chat with George Dyson over at the always reliable Edge -
A Universe Of Self-replicating Code | Conversation | Edge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude Shannon and the Clams</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/claudeshannonandtheclams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/claudeshannonandtheclams/</guid>
      <description>I finished reading James Gleick&#39;s The Information tonite - so good!
Really, the central character is Claude Shannon, who I&#39;m ashamed to admit I didn&#39;t previously know much about. Had a quick search when i finished it and found this decent little 30 min documentary which gives a good overview -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Information</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/theinformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/theinformation/</guid>
      <description>I started reading James Gleick&#39;s &amp;#8220;The Information&amp;#8221; last week and haven&#39;t been able to put it down yet - so good!
I just found this video of a talk he presented at Google last year on the book, looks ace, i&#39;ll save it for watching this evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>robot</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/robot/</guid>
      <description>crazy short film Jim Henson did for the Bell Business Communications Seminar back in 1963 -

// found via Laughing Squid //</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The General and Logical Theory Of Automata&#39;</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/thegeneralandlogicaltheoryofautomata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/thegeneralandlogicaltheoryofautomata/</guid>
      <description>After hearing Ken Hollings read an excerpt from Welcome To Mars at the Atom Town screening last week, I borrowed a copy at the weekend and began reading it. I&#39;m only 47 pages in so far, but it&#39;s already amazing. One of the things referenced in it was John Von Neumann&#39;s 1948 paper &amp;#8216;The General and Logical Theory Of Automata&#39; which &amp;#8220;enlarges upon Turing&#39;s idea of a Universal Machine by proposing a tape-driven, self-producing &amp;#8216;automaton whose output is other automata&#39;&amp;#8221; - A swift google search turns up a pdf of the published paper here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
