<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Howto on The B0ardside</title>
    <link>http://theb0ardside.com/tags/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Howto on The B0ardside</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theb0ardside.com/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Rules of Audio Programming, according to Pete Goodliffe</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/golden-rules-audio-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/golden-rules-audio-programming/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been dealing with threaded data access race conditions between my ui and audio thread this weekend, so found this talk pretty informative &amp;ndash; !
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidalCycles Tutorials</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/tidalcyles-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/tidalcyles-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Alex McLean&amp;rsquo;s TidalCycles has been a big influence on my own Soundb0ard, and lately, now that my instruments are mostly built, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for ways to algorithmically modify them more.
This series of howto&amp;rsquo;s by Mike Hodnick/Kindohm have been an amazing source of inspiration - super clear and very entertaining - here&amp;rsquo;s the first episode:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Henke Granulator</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/monolake-granular/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/monolake-granular/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, my granular synth hasn&amp;rsquo;t quite come together yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m learning a load.
This is a pretty informative (promo) video from Robert Henke/Monolake showcasing his &amp;lsquo;Granulator&amp;rsquo; plugin for Ableton Live.
If i can get mine to sound anything like that i&amp;rsquo;ll be stoked!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let Vim do the typing</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/let-vim-do-the-typing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/let-vim-do-the-typing/</guid>
      <description>Discovered lots of great vim talks - this one is neat:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Schiffman - Purple Rain in Processing</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/purple-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/purple-rain/</guid>
      <description>I was listening to the Creative Coding podcast with Daniel Shiffman the other day - One thing they discussed was Daniel&amp;rsquo;s new Coding Challenges youtube series - this one to do a &amp;lsquo;Purple Rain&amp;rsquo; in Processing is really fun!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android - High Performance Audio</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/android-audio-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/android-audio-performance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on a Brillo audio component, which will require very low latency performance. While searching for some tips and prior art, I came across this talk from Google I/O 2013. A bit older now, but provides an excellent overview of the problem domain and approaches to solving those issues..
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libmill on Randal Schwartz&#39;s FLOSS Weekly show</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/libmill-floss-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/libmill-floss-weekly/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m moving into a new job position soon involving way more code, working in C/C++. I&amp;rsquo;ve just started watching this podcast series and it&amp;rsquo;s excellent - this one in particular is super relevant, bringing one of the best features from Golang into C. I like the minimalism of the project, it seems very much in alignment with the philosophy behind Suckless. (There&amp;rsquo;s a previous episode, speaking with Anselm R Garbe from suckless, i&amp;rsquo;d also highly recommend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Gerrand talking at Go UK 2015 - stupid gopher tricks</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/andrewgerrandgouk2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/andrewgerrandgouk2015/</guid>
      <description>Hah, some awesome bits in here&amp;hellip;
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Program Execution</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/visualprogexec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/visualprogexec/</guid>
      <description>Super fun live demo of program tracing and visualisation from this years Strange Loop conf..
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Storage Drivers</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/docker-filesystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/docker-filesystems/</guid>
      <description>Super nice quick overview of the importance of Copy-On-Write filesystems to Docker, going into detail of the benefits and downsides to each of the CoW options - AuFS, BTRFS, ZFS, Overlayfs, Device Mapper - great stuff!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Debug Anything</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/how-to-debug-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/how-to-debug-anything/</guid>
      <description>Pretty decent talk on debugging methodology..
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Mind</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/joschabach-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/joschabach-ai/</guid>
      <description>Hugely compelling talk by Joscha Bach covering history and possible futures of AI..
  Found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS VPC best practises</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/vpc-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/vpc-design/</guid>
      <description>Super detailed and practical VPC design best practises - very cool stuff..
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joshua Davis - Beyond Play</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/joshua-davis-beyond-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/joshua-davis-beyond-play/</guid>
      <description>Wow. just wow&amp;hellip;
   Tack turned me onto this guy the other day - i love him! Artist/Skater/Hacker - whats not to love?!
This was following me and Tack&amp;rsquo;s Codetraxx project - which is working - we&amp;rsquo;re making music and synchronized via RabbitMQ as we set out to do - however we&amp;rsquo;ve hit a bit of a wall with the algorithmic math behind musical composition, so we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to focus on some mathematical hack nights for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Presentation</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/gopresentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/gopresentation/</guid>
      <description>More and more I&amp;rsquo;ve been dabbling with Go, which, mainly due to Hacker News, i&amp;rsquo;ve been reading so many good things about. The syntax is super easy to pick up, but the killer feature seems to be the concurrency primitives - the Go Functions and message passing Channels seem like a super tight, rock solid implementation of Hoare&amp;rsquo;s Communicating Sequential Processes. The following video is a really succinct walk through of building a concurent multi-protocol chat application ala Chat Roulette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brendan Gregg, Linux Performance</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/brendangregglinuxperformance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/brendangregglinuxperformance/</guid>
      <description>The always interesting Brendan Greg &amp;#8212;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berkshelf - the missing piece</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/berkshelfthemissingpiece/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/berkshelfthemissingpiece/</guid>
      <description>If you&#39;ve been following my past few posts, you&#39;ve seen i was investigating how best to integrate the plethora of Chef testing tools that&#39;ve been coming out &amp;#8212; foodcritic, chefspec, test-kitchen, mini-test &amp;#8212; and although not testing tools per se, Berkshelf and Vagrant are the other pieces of the puzzle&amp;#8230; but how to fit them all together? What is the directory structure for keeping your Berkfile - at the top of the repo?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mo&#39; Chef Testing</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/mocheftesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/mocheftesting/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my last post about Test Driven Chef, this latest Food Fight show is a great roundup of the current testing tools landscape -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test-Driven Chef</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/testdrivenchef/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/testdrivenchef/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m looking to start using Test-Kitchen and Berkshelf, and basically trying to get my head round setting up a proper test driven Chef setup.
I found this video from last year to be quite a good introduction to some of the setup -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix OSS</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/netflixoss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/netflixoss/</guid>
      <description>Found this to be a particularly good episode of The Food Fight show with Jeremy Edberg and Adrian Cockcroft talking about the Netflix tools and architecture:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etsy Scaling vid from 2011</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/etsyscalingvidfrom2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/etsyscalingvidfrom2011/</guid>
      <description>All well accepted practices by now, but still a good watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usenix/Lisa 12</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/usenixlisa12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/usenixlisa12/</guid>
      <description>Just got back from the Usenix/Lisa 12 conference in San Diego, and had a great time, super inspiring talks and content.
Highlight of the conference for me was Brendan Gregg speaking on Performance Analysis Methodologies - most of his talk was based upon a paper he just published in ACM - Thinking Methodically About Performance.
The talks haven&#39;t yet been published on the Usenix website, but Brendan&#39;s blog has a ton of great looking content and older talks including this one on Visualisations for Performance Analysis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Percona Table Checksum</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/perconatablechecksum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/perconatablechecksum/</guid>
      <description>I must admit MySQL replication is something I&amp;rsquo;ve never felt too comfortable with - in most of my positions, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the luxury of working with a full time DBA who would handle all database related work. In my current workplace we have three major pairs of database machines, and have been going through upgrading them all to Percona MySQL 5.5. As you&amp;rsquo;d expect data integrity is of the highest importance, so discovering this Percona Table Checksum tool is a real life saver, providing an amazing tool for verifying and fixing any drift or problems with MySQL slaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>perl parp parp</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/perlparpparp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/perlparpparp/</guid>
      <description>I updated the IP address for both my Name Servers tonite, and was monitoring to see how quickly the new addresses were propagating. First stop was the exceptionally useful Whats My DNS
At the host level I also wanted to track the incoming DNS queries using tcpdump. I could see them streaming into the new host, and visually you could see an obvious difference when viewing the output of the same command on the old host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tcpdump patterns</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/tcpdumppatterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/tcpdumppatterns/</guid>
      <description>I use tcpdump a lot, but mostly at a reasonably high level, only really restricting the capture to host and port info, then pulling the dump back into Wireshark for nicer visualisation and easier filtering.
A couple of months back I read Moonwalking With Einsten, which is a nice pop-science history of the importance of memory in previous societies, alongside the contemporary phenomena of competitive memory competitions. The book is great, and explains how feats of memory are achieved via the technique of memory palaces, a technique dating back to Roman times - spatial memory relationships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet stages and APT</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/puppetstagesandapt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/puppetstagesandapt/</guid>
      <description>At work, our old code deployment strategy was basically a wrapper script doing an svn checkout and some symlinking. With our move to Puppet for config management, we also moved to using Apt packaging for our code deployment, tying them together with a line similar to :
class foo-export {
package { &amp;#039;foo-export&amp;#039;: ensure = latest }
}
So that whenever we deploy a new version of a package to our apt-repo, it can then be installed with a:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant and Chef setup</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/vagrantandchefsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/vagrantandchefsetup/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been reading through ThoughtWorks&#39; latest &amp;#8216;technology radar&amp;#8216; which led me to look up Vagrant, one of the tools they list as worth exploring.
Vagrant is a framework for building and deploying Virtual Machine environments, using Oracle VirtualBox for the actual VMs and utilizing Chef for configuration management. Watching through this intro video:
http://vimeo.com/9976342
i was quite intrigued as it is very similar to what i was looking to achieve earlier when i was experimenting with installing Xen and configuring with Puppet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>