<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on The B0ardside</title>
    <link>http://theb0ardside.com/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on The B0ardside</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theb0ardside.com/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Around the Earth in 200ms</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/aroundtheearthin200ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/aroundtheearthin200ms/</guid>
      <description>A month or two back, i saw an interesting figure on Bram Cohen&#39;s blog:
&amp;#8220;The speed of light in a fiber optic cable around the earth&amp;rsquo;s circumference is about 200 milliseconds.&amp;#8221;
(from here)
I clipped it for my ever expanding Evernote tech tips, thinking it&#39;s one of those useful metrics to know. I&#39;ve referred to it a few times now, but I always like to verify things myself, so this morning I looked up the relevant data -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Von Neumann and the Institute For Advanced Study</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/vonneumannandtheinstituteforadvancedstudy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/vonneumannandtheinstituteforadvancedstudy/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve started reading George Dyson&#39;s &amp;#8220;Turing&#39;s Cathedral&amp;#8221;, and really enjoying it - I love reading the historical context of technological progress, feels like a lot of sociological reading, filling in another of the endless jigsaw pieces of a larger all-encompassing narrative.
Here&#39;s George Dyson doing a lecture on the material in the book :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Networked City</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/thenetworkedcity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/thenetworkedcity/</guid>
      <description>[[ image half-inched from here]]
I started studying Sociology a few years back with the Open University, but never managed to complete my course as I got a job here in the States and turned my study-time back towards practical technology. I did however study it long enough for it have quite a profound effect on my understanding and conceptualisation of networking, and felt especially influenced by the works of Manuel Castells and Stephen Graham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>going google eyed</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/goinggoogleeyed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/goinggoogleeyed/</guid>
      <description>Ah, see, my comic is all true! :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the biology of code</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/thebiologyofcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/thebiologyofcode/</guid>
      <description>Fabulous piece and video chat with George Dyson over at the always reliable Edge -
A Universe Of Self-replicating Code | Conversation | Edge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude Shannon and the Clams</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/claudeshannonandtheclams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/claudeshannonandtheclams/</guid>
      <description>I finished reading James Gleick&#39;s The Information tonite - so good!
Really, the central character is Claude Shannon, who I&#39;m ashamed to admit I didn&#39;t previously know much about. Had a quick search when i finished it and found this decent little 30 min documentary which gives a good overview -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Information</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/theinformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/theinformation/</guid>
      <description>I started reading James Gleick&#39;s &amp;#8220;The Information&amp;#8221; last week and haven&#39;t been able to put it down yet - so good!
I just found this video of a talk he presented at Google last year on the book, looks ace, i&#39;ll save it for watching this evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>robot</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/robot/</guid>
      <description>crazy short film Jim Henson did for the Bell Business Communications Seminar back in 1963 -

// found via Laughing Squid //</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Edge Question 2012</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/theedgequestion2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/theedgequestion2012/</guid>
      <description>The Edge just published their annual Q/A in which they pose a question and ask a group of artists, scientists, and various kinds of intellectuals for their answer. This year the question was &amp;#8220;What Is Your Favorite Deep, Elegant, Or Beautiful Explanation?&amp;#8220;
The list of contributors stretches to 192, most of whom i can&amp;rsquo;t claim to know, however three names I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in stick out:
Rudy Rucker on Inverse Power Laws</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>