<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulator on The B0ardside</title>
    <link>http://theb0ardside.com/tags/simulator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simulator on The B0ardside</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theb0ardside.com/tags/simulator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant and Chef setup</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/vagrantandchefsetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/vagrantandchefsetup/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve been reading through ThoughtWorks&#39; latest &amp;#8216;technology radar&amp;#8216; which led me to look up Vagrant, one of the tools they list as worth exploring.
Vagrant is a framework for building and deploying Virtual Machine environments, using Oracle VirtualBox for the actual VMs and utilizing Chef for configuration management. Watching through this intro video:
http://vimeo.com/9976342
i was quite intrigued as it is very similar to what i was looking to achieve earlier when i was experimenting with installing Xen and configuring with Puppet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record Store Bot</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/recordstorebot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/recordstorebot/</guid>
      <description>First draft of my Record Store Bot is live over on Github - basically tying a Chatbot::Eliza style interface to Last.fm web services for an interactive (hopefully amusing) music recommendation bot.
Works surprisingly well - although only has one method at the moment..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>time travelling with Unix</title>
      <link>http://theb0ardside.com/timetravellingwithunix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theb0ardside.com/timetravellingwithunix/</guid>
      <description>I discovered Unix back in 1998. At the time i was a lowly Windows desktop support engineer when i started dabbling with Red Hat Linux v 4.2. Compared to the process of fixing Windows 3.1 systems ( i.e. reinstall drivers and reboot - if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, reinstall OS and drivers - repeat until it does work), playing with Linux was a joy of knowledge. Every part of the installation process was a problem hiding a wormhole of required knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>